It's not the armor that makes the hero, but the man inside.
Iron Man 2 is a adventure, action, science fiction film directed by Jon Favreau.
With the world now aware of his dual life as the armored superhero Iron Man, billionaire inventor Tony Stark faces
pressure from the government, the press and the public to share his technology with the military.
Unwilling to let go of his invention, Stark, with Pepper Potts and James 'Rhodey' Rhodes
at his side, must forge new alliances – and confront powerful enemies.
Tony Stark, played by Robert Downey Jr..
Pepper Potts, played by Gwyneth Paltrow.
Lt. Col. James 'Rhodey' Rhodes, played by Don Cheadle.
Natalie Rushman / Natasha Romanoff, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Justin Hammer, played by Sam Rockwell.
Ivan Vanko, played by Mickey Rourke.
Iron Man 2 is a 2010 American superhero film based on
the Marvel Comics character Iron Man.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Paramount Pictures, it is the sequel to
Iron Man (2008) and the third film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
Directed by Jon Favreau and written by Justin
Theroux, the film stars Robert Downey Jr.
as Tony Stark / Iron Man alongside Gwyneth Paltrow, Don Cheadle,
Scarlett Johansson, Sam Rockwell, Mickey Rourke, and Samuel L.
Set six months after the events of Iron Man, the film follows Stark as he rejects government demands to share his
technology, which is slowly killing him, while facing the vengeful Russian scientist Ivan Vanko (Rourke).
Development on a sequel to Iron Man began in May 2008
after the success of the first film.
In July, Theroux was hired to write the script and
Favreau was signed to return as director.
Downey, Paltrow, and Jackson were set to reprise their roles from Iron Man, while Cheadle
was brought in to replace Terrence Howard in the role of James Rhodes.
In early 2009, Rourke, Rockwell, and Johansson filled out the supporting cast.
Filming took place from April to July 2009, mostly in
California as with the first film.
A key sequence was filmed in Monaco.
Unlike its predecessor, which mixed digital and practical effects, the sequel
primarily relied on computer-generated imagery to create the Iron Man suits.
Iron Man 2 premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on April 26, 2010,
and was released in the United States on May 7 as part of Phase One of the MCU.
It received praise for its action sequences and performances,
but critics deemed it inferior to the first film.
The sequel grossed over $623.9 million at the worldwide box office,
making it the seventh-highest-grossing film of 2010.
It received an Academy Award nomination for Best Visual Effects.
A sequel, Iron Man 3, was released on May 3, 2013.
The film explores themes of technology, superhero,
malibu, based on comic, revenge.
The tone is thought_provoking.